It’s Just Business.
Enron: The Smartest Guys in the Room is a
documentary film directed by Alex Gibney.
A documentary about the Enron corporation, its faulty and corrupt
business practices, and how they led to its fall.
Narrator, played by Peter Coyote.
Self, played by John Beard.
Self, played by Jim Chanos.
Self, played by Dick Cheney.
Self, played by Carol Coale.
Self, played by Gray Davis.
Enron: The Smartest Guys in the Room is a 2005 American documentary film based on the best-selling 2003 book of the same name by Fortune
reporters Bethany McLean and Peter Elkind, who are credited as writers of the film alongside the director, Alex Gibney.
It examines the 2001 collapse of the Enron Corporation, which resulted in criminal trials for several of the company's top executives during the
ensuing Enron scandal, and contains a section about the involvement of Enron traders in the 2000-01 California electricity crisis.
Archival footage is used alongside new interviews with McLean and Elkind, several former Enron executives
and employees, stock analysts, reporters, and former governor of California Gray Davis.
The film won the awards for Best Documentary Feature at the 21st Independent Spirit Awards
and Best Documentary Screenplay at the 58th Writers Guild of America Awards.
It was nominated for the Academy Award for Best
Documentary Feature at the 78th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of corruption,
capitalism, bankrupt, wall street, scandal.